Trotiner, Glen M.; Papers mss154
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Glen M. Trotiner Papers
1940-2022
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Trotiner, Glen M., 1956-2022
mss154
12.3 cubic ft.
189 Digital Files
This collection contains the papers of Glen M. Trotiner.
Content Description
This collection contains scripts and screenplays written by Glen Trotiner, collected scripts from films and shows on which Trotiner did not work, movie memorabilia and production information from films on which Trotiner was a director and crew member, science fiction research and collectibles, materials from his time as an English teacher and his time as a trainee and board member of the Director's Guild of America, photographs from his personal and professional life, correspondence, and personal journals.
Biographical / Historical
Glen M. Trotiner (1956-2022), a Bronx native and alumnus of the University at Albany, B.A. English '78 and M.S. Reading '79, worked in the film industry for 36 years, primarily as a first or second assistant director. His bodies of work include over 100 movies and television shows, including "The Untouchables" (1987), "Independence Day," (1996) and "Captain America: The First Avenger" (2011). He was also a co-producer on several of his credited works and cameoed as an actor in productions such as "Big Daddy" (1999), "Jungle 2 Jungle" (1997), "Freejack" (1992), and more.
Prior to his entering the film industry, Trotiner worked as an English teacher at Walt Whitman High School on Long Island. He also attended Benjamin N. Cardozo School of Law, receiving his J.D. in 1984.
In 1984, he was admitted to the Director's Guild of America (DGA) Training Program to which he graduated in 1986. Trotiner was a member of the Director's Guild of America from 1986-2023 and served on three negotiating committee as well as the Training Program's Board of Trustees for over 25 years, the longest of any board member.
Prior to his death, Trotiner had goals of teaching and acting as a mentor to future members of the film industry and supported this goal by teaching workshops at the University at Albany.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of several marked folders. These folders are restricted due to personal identifying information within.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2024 by Alison Trotiner Gordon.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is arranged in three series: Artifacts and Collectibles, Writings by Glen Trotiner, and Biographical and Subject Files. The series are arranged alphabetically.
Trotiner, Glen M.,1956-2022; Business and Industry; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Screenplays; Negatives (photographic); Photographs; Motion Picture Authorship--United States; Motion pictures--Production and Direction--United States
- Artifacts and Collectibles, 1940-2013
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains scripts collected by Trotiner of famous works that he did not work on as a member of production or write himself. It also includes movie memorabilia from films he did work on, awards, lanyards from film sets and conferences, production boards, and lifelong collections such as Legion Fanzine, Star Trek, and superhero comics.
  - "Air Force One" written by Andrew W. Marlowe, 1995 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "An American Werewolf in London" written by John Landis, 1980 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Apt Pupil" written by Brandon Boyce, Production Draft #2, 1996 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arista Artists, 1975; 1978; 1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Awards, 2000; Undated (Artifact-box 1)
  - "Back to the Future" written by Robert Zemeckis and Bob Gale, First Draft, 1981 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Back to the Future" written by Robert Zemeckis and Bob Gale, Fourth Draft, 1984 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Book of Skulls" written by Bruce Bernhard and Michael Edwards, First Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Book of Skulls" written by Phil Rosenberg, Mike Lobell Productions Version, 1998 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Boys from Brazil" Revised Screenplay written by Heywood Gould, Final Draft, 1977 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Breaking Away" also known as "Bambino" written by Steve Tesich, 1978 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Citizen Kane" Final Draft, 1940 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Close Encounters of the Third Kind" by Paul Schrader, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Close Encounters of the Third Kind" by Sam Irvin, Second Draft Screenplay, 1975 September 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Close Encounters of the Third Kind" by Steven Spielberg, Revised Script, 1976 April 22; 1976 May 10; 1976 May 12; 1976 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Close Encounters of the Third Kind" by Steven Spielberg, Revised Script, 1976 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Collection Lists, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Dare" Screenplay by Donna Powers and Wayne Powers, First Draft, 1999 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Mr. Deeds" Script, 2000 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Delirious" Original Screenplay by Tom DiCillo, 2005 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Diamond in the Rough: The Maurice Ballard Story" written by Eddie Micallef, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Die Hard" Screenplay by Jeb Stuart, First Draft, 1987 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Die Hard" Screenplay by Jeb Stuart, Revisions by Steven E. DeSauza, Second Revised Draft, 1987 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Edge of Seventeen" written by Todd Stephens, Final Shooting Script, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "The Firm" Uncorrected Draft, 1992 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Forbidden Planet" Script, 1953 August 26; 1954 August 26; 1954 August 31; 1954 September 1; 1954 September 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Fugitive" Screenplay by David N. Twohy, Fifth Draft, 1992 June (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Gods and Monsters" Screenplay by Bill Condon, Shooting Draft, 1997 May 30 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Golden Tux" also known as "Best Man, Inc." by Jeremy Garelick and Jay Lavender, 2013 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Golden Tux" by Jeremy Garelick and Jay Lavender, 2002 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Golden Tux" by Jeremy Garelick and Jay Lavender, William Morris Agency Version, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Guest" by David Darfman, Revisions by David Zucker and Peter Tilden, 2001 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The Guest" by David Darfman, Revisions by David Zucker and Peter Tilden, 2001 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hats, 1986-2023 (Oversize 1)
  - "In the Line of Fire" by Jeff Maguire, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Joe's Last Chance" by Dwayne Alexander Smith, Revisions by Andrew Bergman, 2003 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "The Karate Kid" by Robert Mark Kamen, Second Draft, 1983 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Last Action Hero" by Zak Penn and Adam Leff, First Draft, 1991 September 9 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lanyards, 1986-2023 (Oversize 2)
  - Legion Outpost Fanzine, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Legion Outpost Fanzine Correspondence, 1972; 1973; 1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lost in Space (1 of 2), 1965; 1979-1982; 1992; 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lost in Space (2 of 2), 1965; 1979-1982; 1992; 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Lost in Space" Script by Akiva Goldsman, Revised, 1996 November 15; 1997 February 6; 1997 February 24; 1997 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Lost in Space" Shooting Script, by Akiva Goldsman, 1996 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Magic Hour" by Judith Roberts, 1995 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Momento" Screenplay by Christopher Nolan, Shooting Draft, 1999 August 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Movie Memorabilia, Undated (Oversize 3)
  - "Newsies" written by Bob Tzudiker and Noni White, Rewrites by David Fallon and Tom Rickman, 1991 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "North by Northwest" written by Ernest Lehman, Shooting Script, File Copy, 1958 August 12 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Nothing to Lose" by Eric Bross and Tom Cudworth, Revised, 1994 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Off the Black" by James Ponsoldt, Ninth Draft, 2005 April (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Peter Pan" Screenplay by P.J. Hogan and Michael Goldenberg, Fifth Draft, 2001 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Phaser Fire-Annual Publication of the Science Fiction Club, Bronx High School, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Planet of the Apes" Screenplay by Rod Serling, Second Draft, 1964 December 23 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Planet of the Apes" Screenplay by Michael Wilson, Shooting Script, 1967 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Poseidon Adventure" Irwin Allen's Production of Paul Gallico's Screenplay by Wendell Mayes, Shooting Final, 1971 July 23 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "The Poseidon Adventure" Screenplay by Stirling Silliphant, Third Revision, Shooting Final, 1972 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Primary Colors" Script, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Primary Colors" Shooting Schedule, Crew List, Fedex Receipt, Memo, 1996 November 20; 1997 January 8 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Post Production Gifts, 1989; 2021; Undated (Artifact-box 2)
  - "The Producers" by Mel Brooks, 1973 March (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Production Boards, Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "Second Sight" by Tom Schulman, Patricia Resnick Rewrite, 1988 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Signed Playbills, 1988; 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Star Trek-General, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Superheroes Comic Strip, 1978-1980; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Writings by Glen Trotiner, 1983-2019
  This series contains scripts, screenplays, synopses, and movie presentations for scripts that Glen Trotiner wrote and/or aided in the writing of. Journals and other personal writings appear in the "Biographical and Subject Files" series.
  - "The 9th Dot" Pilot Episode: "Let There Be Light" Written and Created by Glen Trotiner, 2010 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The 9th Dot" Pilot Episode: "Let There Be Light" Written and Created by Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The 9th Dot" Pilot Episode: "Let There Be Light" Written and Created by Glen Trotiner, Final Draft, 2010 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The 9th Dot" Research and Planning Materials, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The American Game" Written by Jeff McArthur and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Bellerophon" Screenplay by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, First Draft, 1985 July (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Bellerophon" Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, First Draft Bound Script, 1985 July (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Code Name" Pilot Episode: "Teleforce" Created by Glen Trotiner, 2007 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Code Name" Pilot Episode: "Teleforce" Created by Glen Trotiner, White Shooting Script, 2007 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Code Name" Second Episode: "Progress" Created by Glen Trotiner, 2007 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "A Day in November" Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "A Day in November" First Draft, Written by Kirk DeMicco and Glen Trotiner, 1993 July (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "A Day in November" First Draft, Written by Kirk DeMicco and Glen Trotiner and Stuart J. Zicherman, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "A Day in November" First Re-write, Written by Kirk DeMicco and Glen Trotiner and Stuart J. Zicherman, 1996 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "A Day in November" Second Draft-Rough, Written by Kirk DeMicco and Glen Trotiner and Stuart J. Zicherman, 1995 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Double or Nothing" Bound, Third Draft, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, 1987 February (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Double or Nothing" First Draft, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, 1986 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Even Steven" Detailed Treatment, Outline and Synopsis, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2000 August 28; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Even Steven" Renamed "The Lease is Up" First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2004 September (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "A Frisbee Game" Written by Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "The Home Field" Working Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2006 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "If, If, If" Original Screenplay, Written by Glen Trotiner, Registered with the Writers Guild of America, 1985 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Images of an Unidentified Script, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "The Last Shot" Screenplay Treatment, Written by Glen Trotiner, Bound and Unbound, Registered with Writer's Guild of America, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Look of Direction" First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 1994 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Love of the Century" Outline for the Screen Adaptation, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "The Ninth Mystery" Bound and Unbound, Screenplay Treatment, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notes Regarding Unidentified Script, Written by Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "The Oath" Bound, Second Draft, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "The Oath" Second Draft and Screenplay Treatment, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "On the Tracks of a Time Traveler" Written by Glen Trotiner, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Overnight Sensation" at Sundance Film Festival, Script and Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Overnight Sensation" Outline, 1997 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Overnight Sensation" Revised Shooting Script, Written by Glen Trotiner, David Garvin, and Eric Fisher, 1999 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Overnight Sensation" Shooting Script, Written by Glen Trotiner, David Garvin, and Eric Fisher, 1998; 1999 January 17; 1999 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Certificate of Registration, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Point of Divergence" First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2014 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2017 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2017 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2017 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2017 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Scene Numbered Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2014 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "The Point of Divergence" Short Film and Series Presentation, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2014 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Smoke Screen" Written by Kirk DeMicco and Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Tear of the Year" First Draft, Written by Glenn Stone and Glen Trotiner, 1985 November (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "The Thirty-First Kid" An Original Screenplay Treatment by Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Unknown Script, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Unknown Script, Notes/Feedback, 2000 May 23; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Untitled" Script, First Draft, written by Eric Fisher and Glen Trotiner, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Untitled" Script, Shooting Script, Written by Glen Trotiner, Dean Garvin, and Eric Fisher, 1998; 1999 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Acts Outline, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Draft Feature Outline, Written by Glen Trotiner and Jacob Wasserman, 2010 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Pilot Episode: "Abracadabra" Written by Jacob Wasserman, 2013-2014; 2014 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner and Jacob Wasserman, 2010 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "You'll See a Tomorrow" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner and Jacob Wasserman, 56 pages, 2010 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "You'll See a Tomorrow" Pilot Episode, First Draft, Written by Glen Trotiner and Jacob Wasserman, 60 pages, 2010 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Pilot Episode, Written by Jacob Wasserman and Glen Trotiner, Based on "If any", Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Presentation Script, Written by Glen Trotiner and Jacob Wasserman, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Script, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2019 August 15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "You'll See Tomorrow" Script Outline, Written by Glen Trotiner, 2014 June 20 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Biographical and Subject Files, 1969-2022
  This series contains photographs, journals, school assignments, correspondence, and materials related to Trotiner's personal life. It also includes materials related to Trotiner's work with the DGA, his time as an English teacher, and his various theater projects.
  - Adorama and SICSI Rental Quotes and Agreements, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Musical and Dramatic Academy Folder with Headshots, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arch Entertainment Bound Pitch Deck, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Awakenings" Daily Production Report, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Awakenings" Production Photos and Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Big Time Adolescence" Online Articles, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Big Time Adolescence" Production Information, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Biloxi Blues" Photos from Filming, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Binder, Crew and Production List (1 of 3), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Binder, Crew and Production List (2 of 3), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Binder, Crew and Production List (3 of 3), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Blueprint of Trinity" Script, 2017 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Brighton Beach Memoirs" Script #000176, 102 pages, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Brighton Beach Memoirs" Script #70, Bound, 132 pages, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Brighton Beach Memoirs" and "The Untouchables" Call Sheets and Filming Location Directions (1 of 2), 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Brighton Beach Memoirs" and "The Untouchables" Call Sheets and Filming Location Directions (2 of 2), 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burnside Entertainment Images and Contact Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Burnside Entertainment Production Service Agreements, 2015; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Career Planning and "Placement" [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Caricature of Glen Trotiner, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cast and Crew photos, Various Films, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "The Cat and the Man Catmaran" Script, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Cat Chaser" Production Board Scan, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Childhood Projects, 1968; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Communications with Billy Mumy, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Color Slides, Filming, 1992; 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "The Confession" Screen Actors Guild Waivers, 1997 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Color Slides, Personal Travel, 1982 August (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Comic About Being on Set, Hand Drawn, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Communications that Accompanied Photos, 1986 December 4; 1990 May 17; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Cast List and Related Documents, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Crew Lists, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Equipment Requirements, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Filming Information for and About Extras, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Handwritten Notes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Legal Clearance, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Location Lists, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Memo, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Memos Re: Editing, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Minor Employment, 1988; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Cop and 1/2" One Liner Schedules, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Player Agreements, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Production Boards, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Production Information (1 of 2), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Production Information (2 of 2), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Production - Tampa Visitor's Guides, 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Reports, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Shooting Schedule, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Cop and 1/2" Storyboards, Notes, Memos, and Stationary, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Crazy People" Production Documents, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Critical Condition" Production Documents, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Daily Handwritten on Index Cards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dean Tarrolly Headshot and Resume, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - DGA Disciplinary Charges of James Price, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - DGA Frank Capra Achievement Award Nomination Materials, 1977; 1984-1987; 2009-2012; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - DGA National Board of Directors Meeting Materials, 2019 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Directions to Producers Offices, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Directors Guild of America, 1989; 1991; 2010; 2021; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Directors Guild of America, Changes and Forms, 2001-2002; 2004; 2007-2008; 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Email Communications with Jonathan Yevin, 2003; 2005 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Envelopes of Registration for Writers Guild of America East Inc., Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Eskimo Sisters"/ "Banana Split" Documentation, 2017-2018; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Experience as an English Teacher at Walt Whitman School, 1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Filmmaking from Script to Screen: Perspectives from the Industry" Course by Professor Segal at UAlbany, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fire Island and "Full Share" Synopsis of Film about Fire Island, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Framed Pictures, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Freewheel Productions, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Girl Soldier" Treatment, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Glen Trotiner '78 Albany to Hollywood" Article, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Glen Trotiner "Digital Resume" Website Design and Redesign, 2010; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Glen Trotiner Resume, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Glen Trotiner Film, 2014 November 1
    This film reel was created as a trailer for the promotion of projects that Glen Trotiner wrote, directed, and shared for public viewing, including: "Heard it From A Friend," "Not That's Fresh!," "Overnight Sendation," and "The 9th Dot." The raw extended videos, music, and branding materials can be accessed upon request.
  - Glen Trotiner School Assignments, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Holly Slept Over" Production Information, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Home Alone 2" Staff and Crew Lists, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - I.D. Cards [RESTRICTED], 1976-1979; 2011; 2022 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Instant Message Communications, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Invitation to "Regarding Henry" Screening, 1991 June 25 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Journal, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Journal of Director's Guild of America Training (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Journal of Director's Guild of America Training (2 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Journal of Teen Tour Trip, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Last Exit to Brooklyn" Bound Script, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Law Materials, 1982; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Script for Professor Segal's Class at UAlbany, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Legacy of a Spy" Script and Outline, 2016; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Legacy of a Spy" Script and Outline, 2018; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Myron Adams RE: Jim Mauro and Mike Marino Dispute on "Cookie", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Looks that Kill" Production Information, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Meadowlands" Production Information, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)